

Peer Christensen

Senior Data Scientist

6+ years experience quantifying patterns in various types of data using R and Python. What sets me apart is a knack for identifying areas in which businesses may benefit from data science and ML. I'm also highly curious about new methods and technology and willing to learn from and share knowledge with my team. In my work, I always aim to exceed expectations and achieve outstanding results.

Copenhagen, Denmark

in dk.linkedin.com/in/peer-christensen-datascientist

+45 5357 1604

peerchristensenportfolio.netlify.com

github.com/PeerChristensen

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

Saxo.com

09/2019 - Present Copenhagen

Saxo.com is the largest online bookstore in Denmark also providing subscription-based access to audio- and ebooks

Main Tasks

- Helping the business define and implement a modern data science strategy
- Developing robust machine learning workflows using R, H2O, Docker and Azure
- Creating NLP-based services and recommendation strategies
- Communicating customer and product insights to stakeholders

Data Scientist

Geomatic

01/2019 - 07/2019 Copenhagen

Data consultancy specializing in data enrichment

Main tasks

- Automating workflows for data acquisition and enrichment for various clients and industries
- Developing core functionality of a self-service app for churn prediction

EDUCATION

PhD student in Linguistics

Lund University

Lund, SE

Selected PhD courses

2014 - Present

- Machine learning in R
- Advanced statistical methods in R
- Text analytics in Python
- Python for developing experiments

MA Cognitive Semiotics

Aarhus University

2010 - 2013 Aarhus

BA LinguisticsAarhus University

2006 - 2010 Aarhus

TOOLS & TECHNICAL SKILLS

R Python SQL H2O Docker Azure

Databricks Machine learning NLP Shiny Tableau

RECENT PROJECTS

Predicting and explaining churn using GBM and Shiny dashboards

Implementing content and item-based product recommendation strategies with NLP and deep learning

Insourcing ML projects saving 17,000 DKK in monthly fees

Developing a novel NLP service for the publishing industry to assess book manuscripts

DATA SCIENCE PUBLICATIONS

An Introduction to Data Science for Ecommerce and Subscription businesses. Book project in prep.

A Guide to Productionizing ML Workflows in Azure. In prep.

A Place for AI in Publishing? Medium, 2021.

Visualizations to Make Sense of Your Customer Feedback. Analytics Vidhya, 2021.

Monitoring Stock Performance Made Easy with R and Shiny. Towards Data Science, 2020.

LANGUAGES

English	• • • • •
Danish	• • • • •
French	• • • • •
Swedish	• • • • •
Italian	• • 0 0 0
German	• • 0 0 0